Thomas Szasz Papers
Thomas Szasz Papers
- Writings by Szasz
  - Book chapters
    - The Right to Refuse Treatment - A Critique, in Who Decides?: Conflicts of Rights in Health Care / Nora K. Bell. Clifton, N.J., Humana Press; 1982 (Box 309)
    - The Right to Use Drugs. Drugs as Property, in New Frontiers in Drug Policy, the Drug Policy Foundation / Arnold S. Trebach and Kevin B. Zeese, with assistance of Carolyn B. Shulman and Kennington Wall. Washington, Drug Policy Foundation: 1991 (Box 309)
    - What is Psychoanalysis?, in Who owns psychoanalysis? / Ann Casement. London/New York, Karnac Books: 2004 (Box 309)
  - Interviews
    Interviews of Szasz published (unless otherwise indicated) in popular magazines, newspapers, and professional journals, and on radio/television programs. Most are American but German, French, and other foreign media are also represented. Interviews for unidentified purpose/publication are filed at the end, alphabetized by name of interviewer.
    - Accent, 4 Apr 1976 (Box 320)
    - The Advocate, 28 Dec 1977; includes drafts, many with revisions/comments; 4 folders (Box 320)
    - All in the Mind, Program #7, undated; transcript of radio or television program, with revisions; 2 folders (Box 320)
    - Art Press International, May 1977 (Box 320)
    - AZ Journal, 23 Jul 1977 (Box 320)
    - Basler Magazin, Oct 1978 (Box 320)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), Nov 1971; transcript of interview (Box 320)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) / television program, "The Myth of Mental Illness presented by Thomas Szasz", Jul 1972; full script of program, including credits, schedule, running order, list of guests, host intro, etc. (Box 320)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), 1983; as published in "States of mind: Conversations with psychological investigators" (Box 320)
    - Christopher Street, Mar/Apr 1981; includes drafts, many with revisions/comments; 2 folders (Box 320)
    - Christopher Street, Mar/Apr 1981; drafts, many with revisions/comments; 3 folders (Box 321)
    - Citizens Commission on Human Rights, Germany, May 1980 (Box 321)
    - The Coevolution Quarterly, no. 18, summer 1978; conversation with California governor Jerry Brown; includes drafts[?] of Szasz's answers; 2 folders (Box 321)
    - Colettivo, no. 26/28, 1981-1982 (Box 321)
    - Cosmos, Oct 1978 (Box 321)
    - Darmstadter Echo, Apr 1977; clipping only (Box 321)
    - Detroit Free Press, 27 Oct 1979 (Box 321)
    - Deutsche Allgemeine Sonntagsblatt, 13 Mar 1977 (Box 321)
    - Family Therapy Networker, vol. 8 no. 4, Aug 1984; includes drafts, many with revisions/comments, and reader responses; 4 folders (Box 321)
    - Focus, Aug/Sep 1989 (Box 321)
    - Le Fou Parle no. 5, Mar 1978 (Box 321)
    - Garde Fous, Feb 1976 (Box 321)
    - High Times, Sep 1981; includes draft with revisions (Box 322)
    - Human Behavior, vol. 1 no. 4, Jul/Aug 1972 (Box 322)
    - The Humanist, Mar/Apr 1973; 1977; includes copy as later published in Szasz's The Theology of Medicine (Box 322)
    - Interchange, vol. 20 no. 4, 1989; in dialog with R.M. Swartz (Box 322)
    - The Journal, Oct 1978; includes drafts with revisions (Box 322)
    - Journal of the Student American Medical Association, drafts only; numerous versions with revisions; 3 folders (Box 322)
    - Laissez Faire Books, 1983 (Box 322)
    - Lektüre Digest, 1978 (Box 322)
    - Medical Economics, 1971; 9 Jun 1975; includes numerous drafts, extensive correspondence with the editor and a few letters from readers; 3 folders (Box 322)
    - Mental Hygiene, 1973 (Box 322)
    - MH, vol. 57 no. 1, other participants: Richard Allen, Dr. Harvey Ruben, Dr. Jonas Rappaport (Box 322)
    - Modern Medicine, vol. 42 no. 20, 30 Sep 1974; includes draft, letter (Box 323)
    - Il Mondo, Dec 1973 (Box 323)
    - Musik + Medizin, Jun 1978; includes handwritten notes (Box 323)
    - The New Physician, Jun 1969; includes reel tape recording of interview - xref to media (Box 323)
    - NZ Panorama, 26 Oct 1974 (Box 323)
    - Penthouse, Oct 1973; includes drafts, many with revisions/comments; 2 folders (Box 323)
    - Phoenix Rising, Jul 1990; on AIDS (Box 323)
    - Profil, circa 1980 (Box 323)
    - Psychologie, Apr 1977 (Box 323)
    - Reason, Oct 1974; 2 folders (Box 323)
    - Review of the News vol. 18 no. 28, 14 Jul 1982; includes draft, with revisions (Box 323)
    - Rheinische Post, 23 Apr 1977 (Box 323)
    - The Rotarian, Oct 1977 (Box 323)
    - Science Digest, Dec 1969 (Box 323)
    - The Sciences, Jul/Aug 1983 (Box 323)
    - Selecta, Aug 1977 (Box 323)
    - Springfield Union, 9 May 1978 (Box 323)
    - Titel, Thesen, Temperamente, 28 May 1980; typed transcript from television program (Box 323)
    - TV Ontario, Nov 1984 (Box 324)
    - El Viejo Topo, Dec 1993 (Box 324)
    - Visāo, Jun 1983 (Box 324)
    - Warum!, Nov 1978 (Box 324)
    - By Böhm, ------ / "Böhm-Szasz Interview", Mar 1970; 2 folders (Box 324)
    - By P.K. / "Medicine and the state", undated; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 324)
    - By Alan Kerr, in Northumberland, Jun 1996; typescript (Box 324)
    - By Pols, ------, undated; typescript of Szasz's answers only, with revisions (Box 324)
    - By Deborah St-Phard, Princeton / "Transcription of interview with Dr. Thomas Szasz", Dec 1986-Jan 1987 (Box 324)
    - By Ronald Swartz, Oakland University / "A Dialogue on education for autonomy", 1984; transcript of taped interview; 4 folders (Box 324)
    - By Randall Wyatt, psychotherapistresources.com, undated; typescript (Box 324)
    - Unidentified, Australian program, undated (Box 324)
    - Unidentified, "Do you think…", typescript, heavily revised (Box 324)
    - Unidentified fragments, undated; typed pages with revisions (Box 324)
  - Introductions
    Included here are prefaces, prefatory notes, forewords, etc. written by Szasz for books by others. Dates given are the publication date of the book or edited volume.
    - The Analysis of sensations and the relation of the physical to the psychical / Ernst Mach, 1959 (Box 325)
    - Breaking the impasse in the war on drugs / Steven Wisotsky, 1987 (Box 325)
    - Critica al giudizio psichiatrico / Giorgio Antonucci, 1993 (Box 325)
    - The Drug solution / Chet Mitchell, 1990 (Box 325)
    - In defense of Schreber / Zvi Lothane, 1992 (Box 325)
    - Madness, heresy, and the rumor of angels / Seth Farber, 1993 (Box 325)
    - The Ordeal of Stephen Dennison / Lucy Freeman and Lisa Hoffman, 1970 (Box 325)
    - Poil de Carotte / Jules Renard, 1975 (Box 325)
    - The Power of life or death: A critique of medical tyranny / Fabian Tassano, 1995 (Box 325)
    - I Pregiudizia e la conscenza alla psichiatrica / Giorgio Antonucci, 1986 (Box 325)
    - Il Pregiudizio psichiatrico / Giorgia Antonucci, 1989 (Box 325)
    - Prisoners of psychiatry / Bruce Ennis, 1972 (Box 325)
    - Psychiatric drugs: The need to be informed / Committee on Mental Health Advocacy, 1981 (Box 325)
    - Psychiatry and freedom / Metamedicine themed issue, 1982 (Box 325)
    - Pure types are rare: Myths and meaning in madness / Irwin Silverman, 1983 (Box 325)
    - The Stoned age / J. Roblowsky, 1974 (Box 325)
    - Textbook of abnormal psychology / N.H. Pronko, 1963 (Box 325)
    - The Therapeutic dialog / Sohan Lal Sharma, 1986 (Box 325)
    - Therapeutic partnership / Carl Goldberg, 1977 (Box 325)
    - Thomas Szasz: Primary values and major contentions / Lee Weinberg and Richard Vatz, 1983 (Box 325)
    - Tools of critical thinking / David Levy, 1997 (Box 325)
    - Wabash Law Journal interview with Szasz, 1969 (Box 325)
    - Unidentified, "Introduction by the special editor", undated (Box 325)
    - Unidentified, "The practice of confining…", undated (Box 325)
    - Unidentified, miscellaneous, short forewords, prefaces, introductions, etc. to unidentified works, alphabetized by opening sentence (Box 326)
  - Letters to the editor
    Szasz was a frequent writer of letters to the editors of newspapers (New York Times, Washington Post),magazines (The Economist, National Review), and professional journals (American Journal of Psychiatry, The Lancet). In many cases these files also include clippings and letters he received from the editors or readers in response.
    - American Journal of Psychiatry, Mar 1958; response to Ian Stevenson, re Szasz's review of "Psychical Research" by Dr. Raynor Johnson (Box 326)
    - American Journal of Psychiatry, May 1959; response to Winfred Overholser, re Ezra Pound (Box 326)
    - American Journal of Psychiatry, Mar 1963; response to Henry Weihofen, re "mind tapping" (Box 326)
    - American Journal of Psychiatry, Sep 1967; response to Dr. Wladimir Eliasberg, re his Psychiatric Justice (Box 326)
    - American Journal of Psychiatry, Apr 1969; response to Fred Sander (Box 326)
    - American Journal of Psychiatry, Jun 1972; responses to R.D. Blair and J.W. Goppelt, re legalizing drugs (Box 326)
    - American Medical News, 25 Jun 1985; response to Dr. John Hanley, re neurology vs psychiatry (Box 326)
    - Ariel, 20 Mar 1973; summary of Myth of Mental Illness (Box 326)
    - British Journal of Psychiatry, 15 Nov 1976; response to Martin Roth (Box 326)
    - British Journal of Psychiatry, May 1977; schizophrenia (Box 326)
    - Bulletin of the Menninger Clinic, Jun 1989; response to Karl Menninger (Box 326)
    - Drug Policy Letter, Fall 1991; the myth of drug treatment (Box 326)
    - The Economist, 17 Jun 1967; mental illness (Box 326)
    - The Economist, 12 Jun 1971; their review of Rogow's "The Psychiatrists" (Box 326)
    - Free Inquiry, Summer 1989; eupraxophy (Box 326)
    - Great Falls Tribune, 9 Sep 1981; John Hinckley, Jr. (Box 326)
    - Harper's Magazine, Apr 1964; response to Stuart S. Turkel (Box 326)
    - The Humanist, Sep/Oct 1969; abortion law reform (Box 326)
    - Inquiry, 20 Feb 1978; response to Robert Andrews, re US and Soviet involuntary institutionalization (Box 326)
    - Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA), 7 May 1960; freedom and the role of the physician (Box 326)
    - Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA), 8 May 1972; psychosis, psychiatry, and homicide (Box 326)
    - Journal of Medical Ethics, Feb 1996; response to Louis G. Daily (Box 326)
    - The Lancet, 11 Jul 1986; response to David Goldberg (Box 326)
    - The Lancet, 22 Aug 1987; AIDS (Box 326)
    - The Lancet, 3 Sep 1988; Koryagin and psychiatric coercion (Box 326)
    - The Lancet, 10 Feb 1990; homelessness, unemployment, and mental illness (Box 326)
    - The Listener, 25 Jul 1974; ECT and other treatments (Box 326)
    - Medical Opinion and Review, Sep 1967; response to Joseph Wolpe, re behavior therapy (Box 326)
    - Mental Health in Australia, exchange of letters with W.B. Grant; includes full issue of journal signed and inscribed by Grant (Box 326)
    - Milwaukee Journal, 8 Feb 1979; involuntary institutionalization (Box 326)
    - National Catholic Reporter, 12 May 1972; addiction as a right (Box 326)
    - National Review, 14 Jun 1966; revision note to article "Mental Health Ethic" (Box 326)
    - National Review, 5 Nov 1990; response to William Tucker, re mental illness as myth (Box 326)
    - National Review, undated; war on drugs (Box 326)
    - Nature, 6 Mar 1972; Zhores Medvedev (Box 326)
    - New England Journal of Medicine, 13 Jan 1972; drug abuse (Box 326)
    - New England Journal of Medicine, 28 Oct 1976; medical ethics and torture (Box 326)
    - New England Journal of Medicine, Jan 1996; response to John Michael Kane (Box 326)
    - The New Republic, 8 May 1976; psychiatry in the courtroom (Box 326)
    - New York Times, 2 Feb 1959; law that would suspend professional licenses of those treated for mental illness (Box 326)
    - New York Times, 25 Jan 1960; cover letter only, enclosed letter is missing (Box 326)
    - New York Times, 5 Feb 1960; neo-Nazis sent for psychiatric evaluation (Box 326)
    - New York Times, June 1966; response to "Dr. Wyman" (Box 326)
    - New York Times, 3 and 10 Jul 1966; responses to readers' letters regarding Szasz's article on mental illness as myth (Box 326)
    - New York Times, Apr 1968; involuntary institutionalization (Box 326)
    - New York Times, Aug 1968; psychiatric language as tool for dehumanization (Box 326)
    - New York Times, 16 Jul 1970; war crimes (Box 326)
    - New York Times, 25 Jul 1970; Zhores Medvedev (Box 326)
    - New York Times, 24 Jul 1972; Ezra Pound (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 26 Dec 1972; stigmatization of psychiatrists and physicians (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 24 Mar 1973; requirement that physicians report names of addicts (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 1 Apr 1974; Ted Morgan's treatment of Francis Barany (Box 327)
    - New York Times, May 1974; Dr. William Summerlin's experiments (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 31 Aug 1975; drug abuse/drug addiction (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 1 Oct 1975; Sara Jane Moore (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 9 Nov 1976; schizophrenia is not a disease, it's an opinion (Box 327)
    - New York Times, May 1977; Freud and psychoanalysis (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 19 Jun 1977; psychiatrists and terrorism (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 25 Sep 1977; Martha Mitchell (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 24 Feb 1979; Robert Torsney (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 29 Jan 1984; Jesse Jackson and separation of church and state (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 27 Sep 1984; war on drugs (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 3 Jan 1985; mental health and treatment (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 21 Oct 1985; drug controls and AIDS (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 28 Oct 1985; schizophrenia (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 6 and 21 May 1987; violence not a disease (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 3 Aug 1987; US and Hungary (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 14 Sep 1987; mental health policy (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 28 Sep 1987; Jesse Jackson, Pat Robertson, and separation of church and state (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 6 Mar 1988; war on drugs (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 20 May 1988; war on drugs (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 23 Jul 1988; war on drugs (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 10 May 1989; crack epidemic (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 13 Jun 1989; crack epidemic (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 10 Oct 1989; true nature of psychiatry (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 12 Nov 1989; foreign aid and Lord Peter Bauer (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 8 Dec 1989; war on drugs (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 18 May 1990; response to Daniel Goleman, and the function of psychiatry (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 19 Jun 1990; Dr. Kevorkian and suicide (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 4 Jan 1991; war on drugs (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 4 Jun 1991; schizophrenia and clozapine (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 2 Nov 1991; private mental hospitals and mental illness as myth; includes letter on back to "Gyruikam" (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 6 Jan 1993; sex predators and coercive therapy (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 1 Oct 1993; tobacco (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 22 Oct 1993; drug addiction as an illness (Box 327)
    - New York Times, May 1994; tobacco (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 9 May 1994; tobacco (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 20 May 1994; tobacco (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 28 Jun 1995; Dr. Kevorkian and suicide (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 26 Dec 1995; Michael Vernon (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 15 May 1996; insurance coverage for mental illness (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 9 Sep 1996; George Soros and marijuana (Box 327)
    - New York Times, 1 Apr 1997; Rancho Santa Fe (Heaven's Gate) suicides (Box 327)
    - New York Times Book Review, 11 Jun 1961; response to Hyman Spotnitz, following Szasz's review of his "The Couch and the Circle" (Box 327)
    - New York Times Book Review, 19 Nov 1995; response to Bruno Maddox, re Karl Menninger (Box 327)
    - New York Times Magazine, 21 Apr 1974; response to Ted Morgan, re Francis Barany (Box 327)
    - Newsday, 1978; Jim Jones/People's Temple (Box 327)
    - Newsday, 7 Jun 1987; mental illness and social policy (Box 327)
    - Newsweek, 28 Mar 1972; response to Peter S. Prescott, re involuntary commitment (Box 327)
    - Newsweek, 5 Jan 1989; war on drugs, AIDS (Box 327)
    - Penthouse (Germany), Oct 1980; drug addiction (Box 327)
    - Playboy, Jan 1971; AAAIMH (Box 327)
    - Psychiatric News, 2 Apr 1976; APA resolution on Zionism (Box 327)
    - Psychiatric News, 20 May 1977; O'Connor v. Donaldson (Box 327)
    - The Salisbury Review, Jun 1989; response to Ryszkard Legutko (Box 328)
    - Science, 27 Jun 1969; response to Gilula and Daniels, on violence (Box 328)
    - Science, Jun 1970; addiction (Box 328)
    - The Sciences, Jan/Feb 1984; response to B.F. Skinner (Box 328)
    - The Spectator, 22 Feb 1975; response to Sargent's review of his Age of Madness (Box 328)
    - Syracuse Post-Standard, 17 Mar 1973; requirement that physicians report names of addicts (Box 328)
    - Syracuse Post-Standard, 12 May 1981; John Hinckley, Jr. (Box 328)
    - Syracuse Post-Standard, 23 Aug 1985; homelessness and mental illness (Box 328)
    - The Tablet, 13 Feb 1960; neo-Nazis sent for psychiatric evaluation (Box 328)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 2 Feb 1973; fanaticism (Box 328)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 25 Jul 1975; 29 Aug 1975; response to C.M. Holloway's review of his Age of Madness, and to other letters (Box 328)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 15 Oct 1976; Ezra Pound (Box 328)
    - USA Today, 11 Oct 1984; NIMH report on mental illness (Box 328)
    - Vancouver Sun, 14 Mar 1973; IQ tests (Box 328)
    - Wall Street Journal, Sep 1988; right to drugs (Box 328)
    - Wall Street Journal, 6 Jan 1994; 11 Jan 1994; therapeutic state; includes publication in Europe edition of WSJ (Box 328)
    - Washington Post, 6 May 1981; John Hinckley, Jr. (Box 328)
    - Washington Post, 16 Apr 1982; John Hinckley, Jr. and the insanity defense (Box 328)
    - Washington Post, 7 Apr 1988; Conan Owens case and the war on drugs (Box 328)
    - Washington Post, 11 Feb 1994; Clinton drug policy and war on drugs (Box 328)
    - Unidentified letters, complete letters, drafts, and fragments; topics include Ezra Pound, Melvin Belli, Alexandr Solzhenitsyn, legalization of drugs, invasion of Panama, insurance coverage of psychoanalysis, AIDS, malpractice, response to a Professor Kendall or Kendell (Box 328)
  - Reviews
    Included here are reviews written by Szasz of books by others. They are published, unless otherwise indicated. Most are reviews of non-fiction books and policy papers, but there are a few of novels, television shows, and other forms of popular culture. The original folders have Szasz's reference numbers on them; these have been clipped and filed inside the new folders.
    - About behaviorism / B.F. Skinner, 1974-1975; includes drafts (Box 328)
    - Acts of will: The life and work of Otto Rank / E. James Lieberman, 1985; includes drafts (Box 328)
    - The Addict and the law / Alfred R. Lindesmith, 1966 (Box 328)
    - All that summer she was mad [Virginia Woolf] / Stephen Trombley, 1982; includes drafts (Box 328)
    - Alongside night / J. Neil Schulman, 1979 (Box 328)
    - Avoiding polarization: The mental health system in the 1980s / James Prevost, 1982 (Box 328)
    - Babi Yar: A documentary novel / Anatoly Kuznetsov, 1967; includes drafts; 2 folders (Box 328)
    - Back wards to back streets / PBS, 1980 (Box 328)
    - Basic theory of psychoanalysis / Robert Waelder, See Psychoanalysis and the family neurosis / Martin Grotjahn, below.
    - The Battered child / Ray E. Helfer and C. Henry Kempe, eds., 1968; includes drafts (Box 328)
    - The Birth and death of meaning / Ernest Becker, 1964; See The Revolution in psychiatry / Ernest Becker.
    - Conversations with children / R.D. Laing, See The Language of madness / David Cooper.
    - The Couch and the circle: A story of group psychotherapy / Hyman Spotnitz, 1961; includes letter from author responding to Szasz's review (Box 328)
    - The Crimes of punishment / Karl Menninger, 1993; part of special feature in Reason on "pernicious books"; includes draft (Box 329)
    - Criminal justice / Abraham Blumberg, 1968; reviewed with Insanity Defense by Goldstein; includes drafts; 2 folders (Box 329)
    - The Criminal, the judge, and the public / Franz Alexander and Hugo Staub, 1957; see also "Recent books on the relationship of psychiatry to criminology" / Szasz (Box 329)
    - Dallas justice [Jack Ruby] / Melvin Belli, 1964; includes drafts; 2 folders (Box 329)
    - The Death of psychiatry / E. Fuller Torrey, 1974 (Box 329)
    - Drug medicalization and prevention act / Washington state, 1997; review of legislation passed in the state of Washington (Box 329)
    - The Economics of mental illness / Rashi Fein, 1959 (Box 329)
    - Elvis / Albert Goldman, 1982; reviewed with Flowers in the Blood by Latimer and Goldberg; includes drafts; 3 folders (Box 329)
    - The Family book about sexuality / Mary S. Calderone, includes drafts; 3 folders (Box 329)
    - Flowers in the Blood: The Story of Opium / Dean Latimer and Jeff Goldberg, See Elvis / Albert Goldman.
    - Freud: The Assault on truth / Jeffrey Moussaieff Mason, includes drafts; 3 folders (Box 329)
    - Freud: A life for our time / Peter Gay, 1988; includes drafts and related material (reviews by others, etc.); 4 folders (Box 330)
    - Freud: The man and the cause / Ronald W. Clark, 1980; includes drafts; 2 folders (Box 330)
    - A Historical review of classification of behavior and one current perspective / Lewis L. Robbins, 1966; book chapter (Box 330)
    - The History of psychiatry / Franz G. Alexander and Sheldon T. Selesnick, 1966; includes drafts (Box 330)
    - In a darkness / James A. Wechsler, 1972; includes drafts, letters in response, letter from Szasz responding to another review (Box 330)
    - The Insanity Defense / Abraham S. Goldstein, See Criminal justice / Blumberg.
    - Landscapes of fear / Yi-fu Tuan, 1980; includes drafts (Box 330)
    - The Language of madness / David Cooper, 1978; reviewed with Conversations with children by Laing; includes drafts; 2 folders (Box 330)
    - Law, psychiatry, and morality / Alan A. Stone, 1984; includes drafts (Box 330)
    - Medical orthodoxy and the future of psychoanalysis / K.R. Eissler, 1966; includes drafts (Box 330)
    - The mind of the murderer / W. Lindesay Neustatter, See "Recent books on the relationship of psychiatry to criminology" / Szasz.
    - Notebooks, 1942-1951 / Albert Camus, Justin O'Brien, 1965; includes drafts (Box 330)
    - On iniquity / Pamela Hansford Johnson, 1967; includes drafts (Box 330)
    - Pain: Its modes and functions / F.J.J. Buytendijk, 1962 (Box 330)
    - Psychiatric reports 2, 4 and 6 / American Psychiatric Association, 1957 (Box 330)
    - Psychiatric studies of Borstal lads / T.C.N. Gibbens, 1964 (Box 330)
    - Psychiatric terror / Sidney Bloch and Peter Reddaway, 1977; draft only (Box 330)
    - Psychiatry and the dilemmas of crime / Seymour L. Halleck, 1967; includes drafts (Box 331)
    - Psychical research / R.C. Johnson, 1957 (Box 331)
    - Psychoanalysis and the family neurosis / Martin Grotjahn, 1960; reviewed with 2 other books (Box 331)
    - Psychoanalysis observed / Charles Rycoft, ed., 1967; includes drafts (Box 331)
    - Psychological disorder and crime / W. Lindesay Neustatter, See "Recent books on the relationship of psychiatry to criminology" / Szasz.
    - A Question of madness / Zhores A. and Roy A. Medvedev, 1971; includes drafts; 2 folders (Box 331)
    - Reality therapy: A new approach to psychiatry / William Glasser, 1966; includes drafts (Box 331)
    - "Recent books on the relationship of psychiatry to criminology" / Szasz, 1958; review/analysis of five books on this topic (Box 331)